#### Contact

+91 96 33 277 947 (Mobile) injackel@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ sureshjohnjacob (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Youth Empowerment
Leadership Training
Sales Leadership Training

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Malayalam (Native or Bilingual)
Tamil (Elementary)
Hindi (Professional Working)
Kannada (Elementary)
Deutsch (Elementary)

#### Certifications

Digital Marketing Certification Course

# Jacob (Suresh John)

CEO - Jacobs' Management Consulting CEO - CrosServe Global Thiruvananthapuram Taluk, India

## Summary

Career Objective:	

- TASK To lead and be a part of a dynamic team in achieving business goals, operational excellence and customer delight, time and again through long and short term strategies.
- PEOPLE- To be a catalyst of professional transformation of individuals in my team and organisation at large, which is possible only through identifying and mentoring next level leaders and nurturing their intrinsic motivation, talents and passion.

# Career Summary:

28 years of experience with Indian and International corporate in General Management, Operations, Business Development, Developing New Markets through strategic, relationship based and data driven approaches, achieving Business Goals and long term client / customer / guest satisfaction. Handling short and medium assignments in / from 15 different countries spread across Southeast Asia, Middle East, Western and Eastern Europe including Balkan region and Americas and the UK.

Key Skills based on Work Experience:

- Strategic Planning - Profit maximisation - International and
domestic Sales and Marketing (Digital, Data driven and traditional) -
General Management & Operations - Client Relations, Relationship
Marketing - Leadership Identification and Development - Building
high flying Teams - Executive Coaching and Mentoring

Industries	worked:	

- Industrial Electronics, IT & Telecommunication - Hotel, Hospitality & Wellness - Management Consulting

#### International Exposure:

\_\_\_\_\_

Travelled and involved in short term assignments in countries other than India:

- Germany Austria Netherlands Belgium Serbia Macedonia
- UAE (United Arab Emirates) Singapore Malaysia Thailand Myanmar Sri Lanka Maldives

#### Leadership Qualities:

-Mission-focused, Result oriented / highly objective -Strategic -Empathetic- Task Vs People balance - Highly self-motivated -Excellent communicator - Extraordinary team player - Seasoned professional

#### Supporting Skills:

- Highly experienced, high energy Public Speaker, Anchor, Master of ceremonies - Web and Print graphic designing - Experienced in result oriented Digital Marketing Strategies

# Experience

CrosServe Global
Consultant at CrosServe Global GermanyIndia
March 2023 - Present (1 year 8 months)
India and Germany

Cross-Cultural Consultant and Coach

CrosServe Global is a cross-cultural consulting firm based out of Germany and India. We do consulting and training in cross-cultural sensitivity and orientation for teams, executives and diplomats who are from Germany or India and is working with people from the other culture.

We have a well experienced team of cross-cultural consultants and facilitators based out of Germany and India who could help you lead, communicate, work and be efficient between Germany and India.

Jacobs' Consulting www.thejacobsconsulting.com Founder & CEO at Jacobs' Consulting April 2009 - Present (15 years 7 months) India

#### Consulting offering:

- 1. Branding and Marketing: Creating strategic product offerings, Brand creation and positioning, Price positioning, GTM (Go-To-Market) strategies, New market entry, International and domestic Sales and Marketing (through digital, data-driven and traditional methods), Relationship Marketing, Profit maximisation.
- 2. Operational Excellence: Planning, Strategising and developing SOPs for Operational Excellence, Client Engagement and Retention Strategies, Client Service Delivery Excellence.
- 3. Organisational Change Management: Catalysing and augmenting positive change to organisations through gap analysis, strategic alignment planning towards management goals and strategic intervention.
- 4. Leadership Development: Identification and Development of Future Potential Leadership, Building high flying Teams, Training CXOs and Business owners in Coaching and Mentoring.

Somatheeram Ayurvedic Health Resort Corporate Director, Somatheeram Health Resort Group December 2013 - June 2024 (10 years 7 months)

Resort: Chowara, South Kovalam Trivandrum

HQ: Somatheeram GmbH, Gartzenweg 2, 40789 Monheim am Rhein, Germany.

An Indo German ownership and management.

Corporate Director in charge of Indian Operations | Strategic Organisational Development | Sales, Marketing and PR | Identifying new SBUs |

Somatheeram is the first ever Ayurvedic Resort in India! 3 times winner of the National award for the 'Best Ayurvedic Resort' and 10 times winner of Kerala State award for 'The best Ayurvedic Centre'.

https://www.somatheeram.org/

Somatheeram GmbH Germany
Unternehmensberater / Business Management Consultant at
Somatheeram GmbH
June 2014 - May 2024 (10 years)
Germany

#### **EUROPEAN HEAD OFFICE**

Somatheeram GmbH
Gartzenweg 2
40789 Monheim am Rhein, Germany

#### Talentpro

National Head - Management Consulting and Corporate Training at Talentpro India

April 2007 - April 2009 (2 years 1 month)

TalentPro is a leading HR company in India offering end-to-end Human Resources Management Services. They provide expert solutions through Management Consulting, Corporate Training, Payroll Outsourcing, Statutory Compliances, Recruitment, TempStaffing among various other services. With an experience of over a two decades, TalentPro is now the leading and preferred HR partner for startups, small and medium businesses, and large MNCs.

#### Club Mahindra

Zonal Manager - Training (South India) at Mahindra Hotels and Resorts India Ltd.

January 2006 - April 2007 (1 year 4 months)

Mahindra Holidays & Resorts India Ltd. (MHRIL), a part of Leisure and Hospitality sector of the USD 20.7 billion multinational Mahindra Group with over 200,000 employees in 100 countries across the globe.

#### NIS Sparta Ltd.

Corporate Trainer & Performance Coaching Specialist at NIS-Reliance Infocomm

August 2004 - January 2006 (1 year 6 months)

NIS Sparta Ltd. (initially known as National Institute of Sales) was then the Asia's largest Training company and owned by the Relaince Group. I was assigned to lead Sales, Channel Management, Leadership and Service

excellence training along with doing Performance and Executive Coaching of Managers of Reliance Infocomm Ltd.

Freelance

Principal Consultant and Master Trainer - Jacobs' Sales Management Consulting

January 1999 - August 2004 (5 years 8 months)

Thiruvananthapuram Area, India

SPIN selling expert.

Sales Management Consultants, Sales Advisors and Sales Trainers.

Helped organisations in enhancing their revenue by improving their market and competition awareness, improving sales processes, training the sales force in selling skills, presentation skills and negotiation skills. Coaching Sales managers to build and manage their teams and to coach their individual team members to enhance their selling skills. Training the Sales and other functional managers in Leadership skills.

IBISys, Software Solutions Founder & CEO - IBISys Software Solutions September 1997 - July 2003 (5 years 11 months)

Thiruvananthapuram Area, India

We were one of the first players in this market in Web Designing, Web Server space rental, Domain name registration, Netvertising, Email solutions

Palmland Tours (Ayurvedic Holidays)
Founder & CEO - Palmland Tours (Ayurvedic Holidays)
August 1997 - February 2003 (5 years 7 months)
Thiruvananthapuram Area, India

Founded and operated Palmland Tours, which was dealing with International Inbound tourists majorly from Western Europe for Ayurvedic Holidays in Kerala. Strategically digitalised the business from the very beginning.

Developed one of the first Tourism and Travel related websites in Kerala and lead the organisation to become successful in bringing clients through digital marketing efforts which we called "Netvertising" when the Internet was not popular in India.

Richsoft Internet Solutions

Manager - Sales and Marketing at Richsoft Internet Solutions

October 1996 - August 1997 (11 months)

ATCO WEIGHING SOLUTIONS CO.Limited. Sales Executive at Atco Weighing Solution Ltd May 1996 - September 1996 (5 months)

## Education

Haggai Institute of Advanced Leadership, Chiang Mai, Thailand Leadership · (2012 - 2012)

Development Dimensions International, Inc, Pittsburgh, USA Workshop Facilitation Skills TTT at Mumbai, India · (2011 - 2011)

#### NIS Sparta Ltd

Train the Trainer, Performance Coaching, Executive Coaching, OBT, Sales, Customer Relations & Leadership · (2000 - 2000)

Indian Institute of Export Management DExM, International Trade · (1996 - 1997)

NSAM FGC, Nitte, Mangalore
Bachelor of Business Management, Management · (1992 - 1995)